

DENINE DEL BALSO

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER/DESIGNER

OBJECTIVE

Having spent 10+ years connecting people with technology in art & design settings, my objective is to take my newly expanded full stack development skill set, and organizational expertise to create solutions for complex problems. I would like to parlay my enthusiasm and passion for creating positive patron experiences into designing intuitive, visually appealing and impactful applications within userfriendly environments

SKILLS

Java
Databases & SQL
HTML5
Object-Oriented Programming
Agile
Libraries/APIs
CSS3
Test-Driven Design (TDD)
MVC
JavaScript(ES6)
Git/Github

EXPERIENCE

LIBRARIAN • AMERICAN GREETINGS • 2014 - PRESENT

- Direct daily business functions as the solo librarian, including cataloging, collection development, reference and budget planning
- Manage the Global Resource Room, which includes supervisory functions and collaborating with Global Sourcing partners

CONTENT METADATA SPECIALIST • FINDAWAY • 2013 - 2014

- Created original RDA Marc records for Playaway devices
- Created and ingested optimized metadata to enhance content visibility

ADULT SERVICES ASSOCIATE • CLEVELAND HEIGHTS PUBLIC LIBRARY • 2012 – PRESENT

 Provide reference, reader's advisory, and computer assistance to the library community

LIBRARIAN • VIRGINIA MARTI COLLEGE OF ART & DESIGN • 2006 -2012

- Provided direct reference assistance to students, instructors and faculty as the sole resource within the academic environment
- Collaborated with instructors to promote information literacy; guest lecturing on advanced searching techniques, website evaluation and the location and retrieval of authoritative web resources
- Designed a library website, utilizing basic web design with HTML, to support the curriculum and the library's services

EDUCATION

CERTIFICATE OF SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

AUGUST 2018 • WE CAN CODE IT

MASTER OF SCIENCE, INFORMATION ARCHITECTURE & KNOWLEDGE MANAGEMENT

AUGUST 2012 • KENT STATE UNIVERSITY

MASTER OF SCIENCE, LIBRARY & INFORMATION SCIENCE

AUGUST 2004 • KENT STATE UNIVERSITY

BACHELOR OF ARTS, GENERAL STUDIES

AUGUST 2002 • KENT STATE UNIVERSITY







